Bart McLeroy

Mediator / Arbitrator

bart@mcleroyadr.com 214-763-2577

Profile

Mediator / arbitrator with extensive experience resolving commercial disputes.

Alternative Dispute Resolution Experience

Financial Industry Regulatory Authority

2015 – Present

Arbitrator for securities industry consumer / broker and broker / employer disputes.

Texas Department of Insurance

2014 - 2019

Mediator for health insurance carrier / provider billing disputes.

Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts

2008 - Present

Arbitrator for property valuation disputes between property owners and county appraisal districts.

Dallas County Courts

2008 - 2010

Settlement week volunteer mediator for civil district courts.

SquareTrade, Inc.

2003 - 2006

Mediator for eBay buyer / seller disputes. Over 1,000 mediations conducted.

McLeroy Dispute Resolution

2002 – Present

Provide ADR services for individual and non-institutional clients.

Real Estate Experience

Jones Lang LaSalle

2003 - 2017

Provided outsourced real estate services for multinational clients. Job duties included consulting, sales, leasing, and portfolio / asset management. Worked with office, retail, industrial, land, and telecommunication sites.

Cousins Properties

Managed lease administration, forecasting, utility rebilling, \$25M in annual collections, and preparation of annual budget for 1.4 million square foot landmark commercial property.

Teaching Experience

Collin College

2018 - Present

Professor of Real Estate

Tarrant County College

2005 - 2016

Adjunct Professor of Real Estate

Education

University of Applied Sciences (Ludwigshafen, Germany) **University of Texas at Arlington**

MBA, Logistics, 2018

University of Illinois

M.S., Real Estate, 2004 B.A., Economics, 1998

Professional Credentials: Texas Real Estate Broker License, Washington Real Estate Managing Broker License

ADR Training: See attached

ADR Training (Current as of March 15, 2020)

North Lake College (Irving, Texas)

Negotiation Skills for Dispute Resolution – 40 hours Mediation: A Comprehensive Introduction – 40 hours Introduction to Dispute Resolution – 40 hours Introduction to Law – 40 hours

Texas Institute for Public Problem Solving

Conflict Prevention and Management – 4 hours

National Academy of Arbitrators

Arbitration Workshop (2005) – 8 hours Arbitrator Training Workshop (2008) – 8 hours Arbitrator Training Workshop (2020) – 8 hours

Association for Conflict Resolution – Dallas Chapter

Mediating & Negotiating Collection Cases – 1 hour

University of Texas at Austin School of Law

International Arbitration – 8.25 hours

University of Wisconsin – Madison

Mediation Techniques for Managing Conflict – 12 hours

State Bar of Texas

Law of Arbitration – 2 hours

North Seattle College

Alternative Dispute Resolution – 50 hours

University of Texas at Arlington

Advanced ADR for Property Tax Appraisal – 8 hours

Texas Mediator Credentialing Association

2017 Mediation Symposium – 6.25 hours

Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts

Arbitration Training – 6 hours

Financial Industry Regulatory Authority

Dispute Resolution: Basic Arbitrator Training – 12 hours

Dispute Resolution: Expungement – 1.5 hours

Universiteit Leiden

International Law in Action: The Arbitration of International Disputes – 10 hours

Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors
Acting as Advocate in Mediation – 1 hour
Arbitration - an Introduction – 1 hour

American Bar Association
Arbitration CLE – 7.5 hours
2019 Advanced Mediation Institute – 15 hours